Guide to the Richard Maass Collection of Westchester and New York State 1645-1995, (Bulk: 1645-1910) MSS 055
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Accretions
  - Subseries B: Letters by and about Benedict Arnold
    - creator: [Arnold, Benedict] place: Head Quarters Robinson's House [West Point, NY], Sep 7, 1780; 055-006-B-2332; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 11)
      dimensions: 14cm x 10cm
    - creator: Varick, Richard place: Head Quarters Robinson's House [West Point, NY], Sep 13 and 14, 1780; 055-006-B-2333; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 12)
      To "My Dear Sir" (Reverend Derick Romeyn) Personal letter to Romeyn at Varick's father's house.
    - creator: Biddle, Clement place: Camp Tappan, Sep 26, 1780; 055-006-B-2334; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 13)
      To Colonel Timothy Pickering. Business as usual three days after Arnold's arrest.
    - creator: Strachan, William place: Tappan, Sep 26, 1780; 055-006-B-2335; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 14)
      To "Dear Sir" (Major Sabastian Bauman) Mention of discovery of Arnold's plot.
    - creator: Bedlow, William place: Clinton House, Sep 27, 1780; 055-006-B-2336; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 15)
      To "Dear Sir" (Colonel Bauman) Requests further news of Arnold's treason.
    - creator: Bailey, Jacob place: Newburg, Oct 3, 1780; 055-006-B-2337; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 16)
      physical description: half sheet, mounted in paper frame; a.l.s.
      To "Sr" Worries about threat from Canada.
    - creator: Lansing, John place: Poughkeepsie, NY, Oct 7, 1780; 055-006-B-2338; 2.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 17)
      To "My dear Sir" (Richard Varick) Offers his services for Varick's defense at court martial.
    - creator: Varick, Richard place: Robinson's House, Oct 10, 1780; 055-006-B-2341; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 18)
      To "Dear Sir" (Reverend Derick Romeyn) Requests Romeyn's assistance at official inquiry.
    - creator: Tallmadge, Benjamin place: s.l., [Oct 1780]; 055-006-B-2342; 25.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 19)
      physical description: bound notebook; MS
      Account of the arrest and execution of Andre [without notes]. 32 page notebook, 25 pages used.
    - creator: Harrison, Robert H. place: s.l., Oct 21, 1780; 055-006-B-2368; 2.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 20)
      Affidavit in defense of Richard Varick's innocence.
    - creator: Clinton, Henry, Sir place: New York, Oct 26, 1780; 055-006-B-2371; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 21)
      To "My Lord" (Lord George Germain) Regarding sale of Captain Campbell's Commission.
    - creator: Parsons, Samuel H. place: Reading, Oct 28, 1780; 055-006-B-2372; 2.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 22)
      To "Dear Sir" (Richard Varick) Regarding documents for Varick's defence.
    - creator: Rodney, George B., Sir place: New York, Oct 30, 1780; 055-006-B-2375; 12.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 23)
      physical description: bound quarto; a.l.s.
      To "My Dear Sir" (Sir George Jackson) Describes arrival in New York and defection of Arnold.
    - creator: Heath, William place: Head Quarters, West Point, Nov 17, 1780; 055-006-B-2388; 1.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 24)
      To "Sir" (Eben Foote) Request for flour and cattle.
    - creator: Meyrick, James place: Parliament Street [London], Jan 30, 1781; 055-006-B-2389; 3.0 pages (Box 21, Folder 25)
      physical description: two half sheets; a.l.
      dimensions: 18cm x 29cm
      To "Sir" (Benedict Arnold) Regarding payment for Arnold's treachery. (contemporary copy)
    - General Notes-Benedict Arnold, 1983-[1989] (Box 21, Folder 26)
      Includes a flyer from Sotheby's Books and Manuscripts Department describing the journal of Tobias Lear (1762-1816) and a letter from Audrey M. Wallace to Richard Maass dated November 9, 1983.